So far, we have mostly seen
目前为止 我们已经大体了解了
how to use GANs for generating images.
如何使用生成对抗网络 (GAN) 生成图像
While generating images is fun, and it
虽然生成图像很有趣 并且它
is connected to several important AI research
与多个重要的人工智能 (AI) 研究方向
directions, it's immediately useful in only a few niche
相关 但它只能用于几个利基
domains, like making image editing software where
领域 例如开发图像编辑软件
the goal is actually to produce a nice image
以最终实际生成
at the end of the day.
不错的图像
A much more generally useful application of GANs
生成对抗网络 (GAN) 的一个更为普遍有用的应用
is semi-supervised learning, where we actually
是半监督学习 我们使用生成对抗网络 (GAN)
improve the performance of a classifier using a GAN.
来提高分类器的性能
Many more current products and services use classification
很多较新的产品和服务使用分类
than generation.
而非生成
So I imagine a lot of you would be
所以我想你们大多数人
much more excited to learn about how
更想知道如何
to build a better classifier than about how
构建好的分类器 而非如何
to generate images.
生成图像
Object recognition models based on deep learning
基于深度学习的
often achieve superhuman accuracy
对象识别模型经过训练后往往
after they have been trained.
能达到超人般的准确度
Modern deep learning algorithms are not yet anywhere
但现代的深度学习算法在学习过程中
near human efficiency during learning.
的效率还不及人类
Consider the Street View House Numbers
想想用于训练地址编号转录模型的
dataset used to train address number transcription models.
“街景门牌号”数据库
This dataset contains hundreds of thousands
此数据库包含成千上万
of labeled photos of address numbers.
地址编号的带标签照片
Recall when you learned to read.
回忆一下当你刚开始识字时
Your teacher didn't need to take you on a road trip
老师并不会带你在整个城市
to see a whole city's worth of address numbers
转一圈 去认识所有地址编号
and tell you what each of them said.
告诉你每个上面的数字是什么
From this point of view, deep learning
从这一点来看 深度学习
seems to require a lot more data than people do.
似乎比人需要更多的训练数据
From another point of view, we could
但从另一点来说 我们也可以
argue that deep learning isn't getting a fair chance,
认为深度学习并没有获得同等的学习机会
because the entire life experience of a deep learning
因为深度学习模型的整个生命经验
model is only a group of labeled images.
只有一堆带标签的图像
People are able to learn from very few examples provided
人能够从老师提供的很少的
by a teacher.
例子中学习
But that's probably because people also
但这可能是因为人还
have all kinds of sensory experience
具有各种各样的感官体验
that doesn't come with labels.
去体验那些不带标签的事物
As we move around the world, we see objects
当我们行走于周围环境时 我们能看到
in several different lighting conditions,
不同照明条件 以及不同角度下
from several different angles, and so on.
的物体等等
We don't receive labels for most of our experiences.
我们的大多数体验是没有标签的
And we have a lot of experiences that don't resemble anything
我们的很多体验在
that a modern deep learning algorithm gets
现代深度学习的训练集中
to see in its training set.
是不存在的
One path to improving the learning
提高深度学习模型
efficiency of deep learning models
学习效率的一条途径
is semi-supervised learning.
是半监督学习
In semi-supervised learning, the model
在半监督学习中 模型可以
can learn from the labeled examples like usual.
正常学习带标签的示例
But it can also get better at classification
但它也可以通过学习不带标签的示例
by studying unlabelled examples, even though those examples
来提高分类能力 尽管这些示例
have no class label.
不具有类标签
Usually, it is much easier and cheaper
通常情况下 获取不带标签的数据
to obtain unlabeled data than to obtain labeled data.
要比获取带标签的数据更容易 成本也更低
For example, the internet is essentially
例如 互联网基本上
a free source of virtually unlimited amounts
是一个免费数据源 提供无限量的
of unlabeled text, images, and videos.
无标签文本、图像和视频
To do semi-supervised classification with GANs,
要使用生成对抗网络 (GAN) 进行半监督分类
we'll need to set up the GAN to work as a classifier.
我们需要将 GAN 作为分类器
GANs contain two models, the generator
GAN 包含两个模型 生成器
and the discriminator.
和辨别器
Usually we train both, and then throw the discriminator away
通常我们两个一起训练 在训练结束时
at the end of training.
丢掉辨别器
We usually only care about using the generator
我们通常只关心使用生成器
to create samples.
创建样本
The discriminator is usually of secondary importance,
而辨别器是次要的
and only used to train the generator.
并且仅用于训练生成器
For semi-supervised learning, we will actually
而对于半监督学习 我们实际上
focus on the discriminator rather than the generator.
主要关注辨别器 而非生成器
We'll extend the discriminator to be our classifier,
我们要将辨别器扩展为分类器
and use it to classify new data after we're done training it.
然后在训练结束时使用它来对新数据分类
We can actually throw away the generator, unless we also
我们实际上可以扔掉生成器 除非我们也想
want to generate images.
生成图像
For semi-supervised classification,
对于半监督分类
the generator is of secondary importance, used only
生成器是次要的 仅用于
to train the discriminator
训练辨别器
So far, we have used a discriminator net
目前为止 我们用了仅有一个 sigmoid 输出
with one sigmoid output.
的辨别器网络
That sigmoid output gives us the probability
这个 sigmoid 输出会给我们
that the output is real rather than fake.
输出为真实而非虚假的概率
We can turn this into a softmax with two outputs,
我们将它变成具有两个输出的 softmax
one corresponding to the real class
一个对应于 real 类
and one corresponding to the fake class.
另一个对应于 fake 类
If we hard code the logits for the fake class to zero,
如果我们将 fake 类的 logit 硬编码为 0
then the softmax computes exactly the same probabilities
那么 softmax 就会跟之前的 sigmoid 一样
as the sigmoid used to.
计算完全相同的概率
To turn the discriminator into a useful classifier,
要将辨别器变成一个有用的分类器
we can split the real class into all of the different classes
我们可以将 real 类拆分为我们想要识别的
we want to recognize.
所有不同的类
For example, to classify 10 different SVHN digits,
例如 要分类 10 个不同的 SVHN 数字
0 through 9, we can make a discriminator
0 到 9 我们可以使辨别器
that has 11 different classes in total, real zeros,
共有 11 个不同的类 real 0
real ones, and so on up to real nines;
real 1 一直到 real 9
and then one extra class, the class of all fake images.
以及一个额外的类 即所有假图像的 fake 类
Now we can train the model using the sum of two costs.
现在 我们可以使用两个代价函数的和来训练模型
For the examples that have labels,
对于带标签的示例
we can use the regular supervised cross entropy cost.
我们可以使用常规的监督学习交叉熵代价函数
For all of the other examples and also
对于所有其他示例以及
for fake samples from the generator,
来自生成器的假样本
we can add the GAN cost.
我们可以添加生成对抗网络 (GAN) 成本
To get the probability that the input is real,
要获得输入为真的概率
we just sum over the probabilities
我们只需要对所有 real 类
for all the real classes.
的概率求和
Normal classifiers can learn only on labeled images.
一般的分类器只能学习带标签图像
This new setup can learn on labeled images,
而这个新的分类器可以学习带标签图像
real unlabeled images, and even fake images from the generator.
不带标签的真实图像 以及甚至是来自生成器的假图像
Altogether this results in very low error on the test
将这些结合起来 最终测试集会获得
set, because there are so many different sources
非常低的误差 因为我们有很多不同的
of information even without using many labeled examples.
信息源 即使并未使用太多带标签示例
To get this to work really well, we
要让它的性能达到最好 我们
need one more trick called feature matching.
还要使用一个技巧 叫作 “特征匹配”
The idea of feature matching is to add a term
特征匹配的想法是向生成器的
to the cost function for the generator,
代价函数添加一个项
penalizing the mean absolute error between the average value
惩罚训练数据上某些特征集
of some set of features on the training data,
的平均值和生成样本的
and the average value of that set of features
特征集的平均值之间的
on the generated samples.
绝对平均误差
The set of features can be any group of hidden units
特征集可以是来自辨别器的
from the discriminator.
任何隐藏单元组
In a paper called, "Improved Techniques for Training GANs,"
在一篇名为 “改进训练生成对抗网络 (GAN) 的技术” 的论文中
Open AI was able to achieve an error rate of less than 6%
Open AI 使用 SVHN 中仅 1,000 个带标签的示例进行训练
on SVHN, using only 1,000 labeled examples.
能实现低于 6% 的误差率
For comparison, the best previous semi-supervised
相比之下 之前最好的半监督
learning algorithm had over 16% error, nearly 3 times higher.
学习算法的误差率为 16% 几乎是三倍
Of course, fully-supervised algorithms,
当然 全监督算法
using hundreds of thousands of labeled examples,
使用成千上万的带标签示例进行训练
are able to achieve less than 2% error.
能够实现低于 2% 的误差率
So semi-supervised learning still
所以相比收集巨量带标签数据
has some catching up to do compared to the brute force
进行训练的蛮力方法
approach of just gathering tons and tons of labeled data.
半监督学习仍然还有很大差距
Usually, labeled data is the bottleneck
一般来说 带标签数据是一个瓶颈
that determines which tasks we are or aren't able to solve
它决定了我们用机器学习能或不能
with machine learning.
解决哪些任务
Hopefully using semi-supervised GANs,
希望使用半监督生成对抗网络 (GAN)
you'll be able to tackle a lot of problems
你可以解决之前无法解决的
that weren't possible before.
很多问题